



2018.01 - 2018.08



header 1: Montserrat Regular

UX Design Intern

BLACKBERRY LIMITED

I worked on the BlackBerry Hub+ Android application suite and BlackBerry Secure Android. In this project I...

- Collaborated with project managers and developers to solve complex interface and product experience problems
- Created wireframes, , and technical red line specs
- Built interactive prototypes and conducted usability testing
- Designed icons to communicate interactions and information
- Animated interface interactions to design effective visual feedback



heading text

SUBHEADING

body text body text body text. Zachary Chan. ZACHARY CHAN. Portfolio. Experiences. Skills. Achievements.

Header 2 Lato Black 14pt (180 s

HEADER 2 LATO REGULAR 10PT (140 SPACE)

Header 4 Lato Black 10pt (100 space)

body text body text body text. Zachary Chan. ZACHARY CHAN. Portfolio. Experiences. Skills. Achievements. Lato Light 10pt (40 space)

h

I'm passionate about solving problems and creating work that inspires others. My drive is wielded through my background as a **designer** specializing in interaction and user experience. I'm a front-end web **programmer** and I'm also a **visual thinker**. love collaborating with others and understanding the lenses that my peers and my end users experience the world through so that I can execute ideas in strong and impactful solutions.

skills

Design Research	Sketching	Motion Design	Videography
Ideation	Wireframing	3D Modelling	Market Research
User Testing	Prototyping	Photography	Business Analysis

toolbox

DESIGN PROGRAMS

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

After Effects

Premiere

Maya

Solid Works

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML

CSS

Javascript

SQL

PHP

Bootstrap

Java

1yr 2yrs 3yrs 4yrs +5yrs

experience

UX Design Intern

BLACKBERRY LIMITED

I worked on the BlackBerry Hub+ Android application suite and BlackBerry Secure Android. In this project I...

- Collaborated with project managers and developers to solve complex interface and product experience problems
- Visualized concepts with wireframes, interactive prototypes, and technical red line specs created with Adobe Suite software
- Conducted usability testing
- Designed icons to communicate interactions and information
- Animated interface interactions to design effective visual feedback

Web Designer/Developer

ALVIS TSUI (FSS) INC.

I created online application forms and a searchable database of FSS' school information to extend their services beyond telephone and in-office mediums. In this project I...

- Sketched and built interactive wireframes in Axure RP Pro
- Developed a responsive step-by-step application form with PHP, JavaS-cript, and PHPMailer
- Designed database architecture and built database with SQL
- Programmed end user pages to traverse database

User Research & UX Design

2017.05 - 2017.08

2017.05 - 2017.12

2018.01 - 2018.08

FIT FIRST RUN CLUB (academic project)

Designed a digital and physical community interface to set and track running goals to enhance the collaborative nature motivation of members of the run club. In this project I...

- Conducted research through interviews, group participation, culture probes, informance videos, and user testing.
- Created user personas and journey maps
- Designed interface of the interactive kiosk
- Filmed, animated, and edited final project video.



education

SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

Interactive Arts & Technology
BSc Concentration in design

Beedie School of Business Minor

extra zach

(INTERESTS)



Drawing



Hiking



Exercising



Movies



Nerdiness

experience

User Research & App Design

DIS • COVERED MOBILE APP

In a team of 4, I designed a mobile application with the goal of aiding refugees and immigrants new to Canada with the often daunting task of discovering and integrating into their new community. In this project I...

- Researched the user group of Middle-Eastern refugees and immigrants to find potential for a design solution.
- Created user personas and journey maps.
- Ideated unique micro-interactions for the different app functions.

Product Design

ARTHRITIC FLASHLIGHT

2017.05 - 2017.12

2018.01 - 2018.08

In a product design course, myself and 2 teammates designed a flashlight with improved usability for people suffering from arthritis. In this project I...

- Conducted user and product research to design to the ideal ergonomic proportions of a specific user group.
- Ideated through sketching and blue foam modelling.
- Rendered final product form with Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop after further iteration on the flashlight design.

leadership

BlackBerry Student Social Committee

MEDIA EXECUTIVE

The BSSC is a student run committee devoted to creating a supportive, social network for interns working at BlackBerry through fun events in and outside the office. We also organize a special panel each semester to have executive leadership team members share their experience with co-ops. I created promotional materials and helped organize events.

Interactive Arts & Technology Student Union

2016.05 - 2017.04

2018.01 - 2018.04

SECRETARY & COUNCILLOR

The IAT student union organizes events for students in the Interactive Arts and Technology program at SFU. I recorded meeting minutes, organized events, and helped with social media campaigns marketing as union Secretary and represented SIAT students' interests as the IAT Councillor at the Simon Fraser Student Society student government as IAT Councillor

zach chan **UX** Designer

education

Simon Fraser University 2013 - 2020 (ongoing)

B/Sc Interactive Arts & Technology Minor Beedie School of Business w/ Co-operative Education

skills

Design Research + Ideation Prototyping + User Testing Wireframing + 3D Modelling Motion Design + Videography Brand + Market Research + **Business Analysis**

tools

Adobe Creative Suite AxureRP + Figma Maya + Unity HTML5 + CSS3 + Javascript Git + PHP + SQL

extra zach

(interests)





Drawing





Hiking



Nerdiness

about me

I'm a **UX designer** specializing in web, mobile, and 3D space environments. My background is in **front-end web development** but I love to continuously learn and find inspiration in new technologies. I'm a visual thinker who loves collaborating and understanding the lenses of my peers and users so that I can execute ideas in delightful, efficient solutions.

experience

UX Design Intern

BlackBerry Ltd. || Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

I worked on the BlackBerry Hub+ Android application suite and BlackBerry Secure Android OS. During my time here I collaborated with project managers, developers, and other designers to solve complex interface and product experience problems.

- Designed + shared UI/UX through sketches, wireframes, and technical specs
- Conducted user research, market research, and usablity testing
- Created icons and animated UI interactions
- Designed internal asset manager library to improve workflow

Web Designer/Developer

Alvis Tsui (FSS) Inc. | May 2017 - Dec. 2017

I created web application forms and a searchable database of FSS' school information to extend their services beyond telephone and in-office mediums. I controlled the full end-to-end design and development of this project.

- Built interactive wireframes in Axure RP
- Programmed responsive web pages with PHP, JavaScript, and PHPMailer
- Designed database architecture and built database with SQL
- Created user manual to handoff completed tool to FSS employees

projects

User Research & UX Design

Fit First Run Club | May 2017 - Aug. 2017

In a team of 3, I conducted extensive user research that led to designing a digital community interface to set and track collaborative running goals so that the connectivity and motivation of members of the running club would be enhanced. After the design phase, I filmed, animated and edited a summative project showcase video.

User Research & App Design

DIS • COVERED Mobile App || Jan. 2018 - Mar. 2018

In a team of 4, I researched and designed a mobile application with the goal of aiding refugees and immigrants new to Canada who are facing the daunting task of discovering and integrating into their new community. I did background research and designed micro-interactions in the final prototype.